Hello and welcome to Real easy English In this podcast, we have real conversations in easy English to help you learn I'm Neil and I'm Georgie.
You can find a video version of this podcast with subtitles on our website, BBClearningenglish.com. .
Hi Georgie, how are you I'm very well thank you Neil how are you I'm okay at the weekend I went to a concert Yes and I was trying
To listen to the music lots of people around me were talking loudly and I really hate that Oh it's quite annoying I guess yeah
Well today we're actually talking about things that we don't like things that we hate doing and things that we don't like.
Other people doing so let's talk about your concert then how why didn't you like that I just think it'sum it feels quite rude to me
Because lots of people, Want to listen to the music and they paid money to listen to the music,
But other people have decided just to talk and it means I couldn't listen to my.
My favorite music yeah and the tickets are expensive and you go there for a reason and other people can ruin the experience for you this happens also
In the cinema or the theatre yeah I find that.
Annoying too I don't like it when people when groups of people are walking down the street in a line and they don't leave space for other
People to pass.
I can sometimes be a bit impatient and maybe that's my problem, but yeah that that annoys me Do you know what I can't stand What?
I can't stand it when people leave litter or rubbish, especially in a beautiful natural place so if I'm in the countryside
And then I see some old rappers or cans cans left lying on the ground that makes me sad and angry
Yeah because it spoils the beautiful environment is there anything that you hate doing personally?
Oh lots of things I really hate DIY DIY is when you do repairs to your own house or flat
Yes I'm really bad at it and because I know I'm bad at it when I do it and it's a failure
Everything about it makes me hate it Another thing that I don't like doing is similar to what I said before.
I don't like going through crowds of people because again, I like to get to places quickly and if I can't move easily in a crowd that frustrates
Me, I find that annoying.
And irritating Yeah it's really irritating isn't it it's strange because usually I'm quite a calm and relaxed person and I just think, well, whatever happens happens, but for some reason in these situations I get, Very annoyed.
It makes me very annoyed.
How about food, Is there any food that you can't stand Actually, no, I eat most food and I really love food.
When I was younger, I used to hate nuts for some reason, I don't like the texture but or I didn't like the texture,
But now I think I don't mind them so much, I just don't want, Nuts in my sweet treats so Neil,
Do you think that there's anything that you do that other people hate Oh definitely.
I've got kids and kids are very honest and so my kids think I'm really annoying in the morning, especially if I ask them lots of questions when they're.
Making their breakfast I can really relate to that to your kids actually because I really don't like it when people ask me lots of questions in the morning I'm just waking
Up, I don't want to talk to anyone at the moment.
Anything else well probably lots but let's leave it there How about you there's death and any things that people find annoying about me I'm
Very forgetful with my possession so things that, I own, I often leave bags,
Phones, jackets, umbrellas in restaurants and bars, and my friends and my sister get really annoyed.
Because they have to follow me around making sure that I've got all of my things and I think that's very annoying for them it's annoying for me as well because I lose lots of things like my phone
A couple of times.
An for everyone Okay, let's recap the vocabulary we've heard in this episode starting with can't stand.
If you can't stand something, you really, really don't like it the adjectives annoying and irritating.
Describe something that makes you feel uncomfortable or angry when it happens Georgie just gave the adjectives that describe the situation, but annoyed or irritated, describe the way you feel.
So if you are annoyed or irritated, something has made you angry if you feel frustrated, you're annoyed because you can't do something, for example if you're in a traffic jam, you can feel frustrated that you can't move somewhere quickly.
The situation is frustrating That's it for this episode of real easy English but don't forget to go to our website BBC Learning English.com. where you can download a free worksheet.
And we'll be back next week with another conversation in Easy English goodbye for now goodbye.